Guide to the McKinney Family Papers, 1823-1964
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES VIII. Ethelyn McKinney
  - Quill Jones tag, undated (Folder 20.32)
  - Letter to Mrs. Louis Connor from Ethelyn [Greenwich, Conn.], 14 June 1937 (Folder 20.33)
  - Drawing of llamas and mountain titled, "Alpie del Mistri", [1940] (Folder 20.34)
  - Letters to Ethelyn from various art institutions re: Childe Hassan's "Allies Day, May 1917", 1 Dec 1930 -19 Aug 1948 (Folder 20.35)
  - Letters to Ethelyn from various art institutions re: Childe Hassan's "Union Square" and " Madison Square, NY", 1 June 1925 - 5 May 1943 (Folder 20.36)
  - Telegram to Ethelyn from Carleton, 29 Apr 1941 (Folder 20.37)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Ms. Horace Bigelow [Wilton, Conn.], 15 Feb 1945 (Folder 20.38)
  - Postcard to Ethelyn from Margaret Grierson, 16 Dec 1951 (Folder 20.39)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Charleton S. Connor [New York], 30 Jan 1950 (Folder 20.40)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from the Board of Trustees of the First Presbyterian Church in Titusville, Pa, 18 Oct 1952 (Folder 20.41)
  - Announcement of acceptance of Charleton S. Connor into Cummings and Lockwood law firm, 1 July 1953 (Folder 20.42)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from [Bertie and Hilda?], 7 Dec 1953 (Folder 20.43)
  - Article by Eleanor Roosevelt, Nov 1942 (Folder 20.43)
  - Obituary of William W. Barker, undated (Folder 20.43)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Charleton S. Connor [Stamford, Conn.], 20 Apr 1954 (Folder 20.44)
  - List of active members in the Mystery Club, Sept 1954 (Folder 20.45)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from the Museum of the City of New York, 27 Sept 1955 (Folder 20.46)
  - Ethelyn's passport no. 143188, 19 July 1956 (Folder 20.47)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Charleton S. Connor, 17 Apr 1956 (Folder 20.48)
  - Pamphlets for the Edgewood School, undated (Folder 20.49)
  - Letter to Esta Halper form R.L. Von Tacky of the Titusville Trust Co., 29 June 1957 (Folder 20.50)
  - Christmas card from [Kim?], 25 Dec 1957 (Folder 20.51)
  - Letter to Jean and Ralph Connor from Philip M. Drake of The Greenwich Time, 22 June 1964 (Folder 20.52)
  - Ethelyn's obituary, 18 June 1964 (Folder 20.52)
  - Letter from Headmaster Thomas E. Purdy re: Ethelyn's "significant gift to Oakwood School", 11 Sept 1964 (Folder 20.53)
  - Photo of Ethelyn and Jean Webster McKinney (Mrs. Connor), undated (Folder 20.54)
  - Postcard to Ethelyn from Beatrice Sleeter, undated (Folder 20.54)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from the Duchess of Somerset, 4 Sept [1939?] (Folder 20.54)
  - Diary, 1885 (Folder 21.1)
  - Accounts and Notes, 1886 (Folder 21.2)
  - Diary, 1889 (Folder 21.3)
  - Diary, Jan 1890 -Oct 1891 (Folder 21.4)
  - Diary, Nov 1891 -Aug 1892 (Folder 21.5)
  - Diary, May - June 1896 (Folder 21.6)
  - Diary, July - Sep 1896 (Folder 21.7)
  - Diary, Feb - Mar 1897 (Folder 21.8)
  - Diary, Sept 1897 (Folder 21.9)
  - Address book, 1897 (Folder 21.10)
  - Diary and address book, 1898 (Folder 22.1)
  - Diary and Werkbuch fur Theater-Concerte, 1899; (2 vols.) (Folder 22.2)
  - Art notes, 1900 (Folder 22.3)
  - Line a Day book, 1900 (Folder 22.4)
  - Diaries, 1901-1904 (Folder 22.5)
  - Diary, 1905 (Folder 22.6)
  - Diaries, 1906; (2 vols.) (Folder 22.7)
  - Account book (travel), 1907 (Folder 22.8)
  - Line a day book, 1908 (Folder 22.9)
  - Line a day book, 1912 (Folder 22.10)
- SERIES IX. Photographs
  - McKinney Family
    - Glenn Ford McKinney
      - Youth (Folder 23.1)
      - Princeton (Folder 23.2)
      - Later Life (Folder 23.3)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 23.4)
    - Ida Ethelyn McKinney
      - Youth (Folder 23.5)
      - Smith College (Folder 23.6)
      - Later life (Folder 23.7)
      - Friends and Miscellaneous (Folder 23.8)
    - Ida DeEtte Ford McKinney (Folder 24.1)
    - John C. Ford (Folder 24.2)
    - Jerusha Jane Dalrymple Ford Photos (Folder 24.3)
    - Lila Dalrymple (Folder 24.4)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 24.5)
  - Moffett Family Photographs
    - Pamela Clemens Moffett (Folder 24.6)
    - Anita Clemens Moffett (Folder 24.7)
    - William A. Moffett (Folder 24.8)
    - Samuel Moffett (Folder 24.9)
    - Samuel Moffett and Annie Moffett (Webster), circa 1869 (Folder 24.10)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 24.11)
    - S.E. Moffett's childhood photograph album (Folder 27.1)
    - Broken ambrotype of William A. and Pamela Moffett (Folder 27.7)
  - Webster Family Photographs
    - Annie Moffett Webster, undated (Folder 26.1)
    - Annie Moffett Webster (at 3 years old) (Folder 27.4)
    - Jean Webster with Jane Clemens, Annie Moffett Webster, Pamela Clemens Moffett (The "4 Generations" photograph), 18 June 1882 (Folder 26.2)
    - Samuel Webster (Folder 26.3)
    - Luther Webster (Folder 26.4)
    - Maria Whitney Webster (Folder 26.5)
    - Luther and Maria Whitney Webster on their wedding day (Daguerreotype given to Jean Webster by Sam Webster inJune 1934), 1848 (Box 28)
    - Charles L. Webster (Folder 26.6)
    - William Webster (Folder 26.7)
    - Webster Family Album (miniatures) (Folder 27.2)
    - Annie Moffett Webster's photograph album (Box 28)
    - Charles L. Webster's photograph album, 1863 (Box 28)
    - Calvin Whitney silhouette (Folder 27.5)
    - Maria Whitney silhouette (Folder 27.6)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 26.8)
  - Clemens Family
    - Samuel L. Clemens
      - Portrait, tin type of daguerreotype, 1853 (Folder 25.1)
      - Photo of portrait painting in Keokuk Library, circa 1857 (Folder 25.2)
      - Portrait, 1859 (Folder 25.3)
      - Portrait, 1862; (2) (Folder 25.4)
      - with Charlie Langdon, circa 1868 (Folder 25.5)
      - with George Alfred Townsend and David Gray, 7 Feb 1871 (Folder 25.6)
      - Portrait, in fur hat, circa 1872 (Folder 25.7)
      - Portrait, in London, Nov 1873 (Folder 25.8)
      - At desk, stereopticon, 1873 (Folder 25.9)
      - Portrait, looking left, 1874 (Folder 25.10)
      - Portrait, looking right, 1874 (Folder 25.11)
      - with Susie and Clara Clemens, circa 1877 (Folder 25.12)
      - Portrait, 1883 (Folder 25.13)
      - with Unidentified man, 18 Dec 1883 (Folder 25.14)
      - with George Cable and the family if Erasmus Mason Moffett, 13 Jan 1885 (Folder 25.15)
      - Portrait, copy, circa 1905 (Folder 25.16)
      - with Isabel Lyon and Jean Clemens, 16 May 1906 (Folder 25.17)
      - Photo of portrait painting at Lotus Club, New York, N.Y., 1906 (Folder 25.18)
      - with Rudyard Kipling and others at Oxford, 26 June 1907 (Folder 25.19)
      - with others at wedding of Clara Clemens, 6 Oct 1909 (Folder 25.20)
      - in Bed, circa 1900 (Folder 25.21)
      - Portrait postcards, circa 1900; (2) (Folder 25.22)
      - Birthplace, undated (Folder 25.23)
      - Steamboat "Mark Twain", undated (Folder 25.24)
      - Typesetter press at Twain Memorial, Hartford, CT, undated (Folder 25.25)
    - Olivia Clemens (Folder 25.26)
    - Olivia Clemens and children (Folder 25.27)
    - Susie, Clara and Jean Clemens (Folder 25.28)
    - Clara Clemens (Folder 25.29)
    - Susie Clemens (Folder 25.30)
    - Jean Lampton Clemens (Folder 25.31)
    - Langdon and Clemens children, 1887 (Folder 25.32)
    - Jane Lampton Clemens (Folder 25.33)
    - Orion Clemens (Folder 25.34)
    - Jennie Clemens (Folder 25.35)
    - Henry Clemens (Folder 27.3)
    - Unidentified female member of the family (Folder 25.36)
    - Photocopies of photos fumigated by Rendall (Folder 25.37)
  - Miscellaneous Photos
    - Unidentified Tintype (Male) (Box 28)
    - Unidentified Tintype (Female) (Box 28)
    - C.L. Webster's Photographs of Ulysses S. Grant (Box 28)
- SERIES X. Ephemera
  - Annie Moffett Webster's music book (Box 28)
  - "Family Chronicle", written by Annie Moffett Webster describing the history of the Moffett and Webster families (Box 28)
  - copy of "Whitewashing Jane Clemens" in The Bookman, July 1925 (Box 28)
  - Plaster cast of Ulysses S. Grant's Congressional Gold Medal (Box 28)